{"test_questions": [[{"question": "The ability of Vibrio fischeri to convert chemical energy directly into radiant energy in bioluminescence is an example of __________ at work.", "opta": "Shelford's law of tolerance", "optb": "Leibig's law of the minimum", "optc": "the first law of thermodynamics", "optd": "the third law of thermodynamics", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The ability of a competitive inhibitor to bind to an active site in an allosterically controlled enzyme is __________ than the ability of a non-competitive inhibitor to bind to an active site in the same allosterically controlled enzyme.", "opta": "greater", "optb": "lesser", "optc": "approximately equal", "optd": "half", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The ability of FADH to be oxidized is __________ than the ability of FAD to be oxidized.", "opta": "greater", "optb": "lesser", "optc": "approximately equal", "optd": "half", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "An endergonic reaction is one that", "opta": "requires energy in order to proceed", "optb": "releases energy for work", "optc": "gives off much heat", "optd": "looses energy", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Reduction is the", "opta": "loss of proton", "optb": "gain of electron", "optc": "loss of electron", "optd": "gain of protons", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If the Keq for an enzymatic reaction is greater than 1, the reaction", "opta": "will be endergonic", "optb": "can not occur without the input of energy", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "An exergonic reaction is one that", "opta": "requires energy to proceed", "optb": "releases energy for work", "optc": "gives off much heat", "optd": "looses energy", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If the free energy change (\u0394G) in a reaction is a negative value, it indicates that the", "opta": "reaction releases energy", "optb": "reaction absorbs energy", "optc": "reaction is in negative direction", "optd": "reaction is in positive direction", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "To a living organism, which of the following has the greatest amount of available energy per molecule?", "opta": "ATP", "optb": "ADP", "optc": "AMP", "optd": "H2O", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is the best evidence for the lock and key theory of enzyme action?", "opta": "Compounds similar in structure to the substrate inhibit enzyme activity", "optb": "Enzymes are found in living organisms and speed up certain reactions", "optc": "Enzymes speed up reactions by definite amounts", "optd": "Enzymes determine the direction of a reaction", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In the reaction, C6H12O6+ 6O2 \u2192 6CO2 + 6H2O + energy, which component is being oxidized?", "opta": "C6H12O6", "optb": "O2", "optc": "CO2", "optd": "H2O", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The fact that \u03b2-oxidation of fatty acids, occurs in the mitochondria whereas fatty acid synthesis occurs in the cytoplasmic matrix, is an example of regulation of enzymatic activity by the __________ mechanism.", "opta": "compartmentation", "optb": "induction", "optc": "competitive inhibition", "optd": "repression", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In the reaction, C6H12O6 + 6O2 \u2192 6CO2 + 6H2O + energy, which component is being reduced?", "opta": "O2", "optb": "CO2", "optc": "H2O", "optd": "Energy", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The affinity of an enzyme for its substrate, when the enzyme has a Km of 0.50 M will be __________ than the affinity of an enzyme for its substrate when the enzyme has a Km of 0.05 M.", "opta": "greater", "optb": "lesser", "optc": "approximately equal", "optd": "half", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Anthranilate synthase, the first enzyme of tryptophan biosynthesis after the branch point shows feedback inhibition and repression due to", "opta": "L-tryptophan", "optb": "D-L-tryptophan hydantoin", "optc": "L-serine", "optd": "pyruvate", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A substrate binds to its enzyme at a location called the __________ site.", "opta": "coenzyme", "optb": "substrate", "optc": "active", "optd": "polypeptide", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Hydrogen and oxygen release enormous amounts of energy when they react. Yet, hydrogen and oxygen can be mixed together in a balloon and nothing will happen. Why?", "opta": "Competitive inhibitors are blocking the reaction from occurring in the active site", "optb": "There must be contaminating elements in the balloon that prohibit the reaction from occurring", "optc": "The energy of activation to form the transition-state complex is too high to allow the reaction to occur without assistance", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Adenosine triphosphate is a type of", "opta": "fatty acid", "optb": "amino acid", "optc": "nucleotide", "optd": "steroid", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "An enzyme that is always produced, regardless of the presence of substrates or the end products, is called", "opta": "a constitutive enzyme", "optb": "an isoenzyme", "optc": "a repressible enzyme", "optd": "an allosteric enzyme", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "About 7.3 kcal/mole are released when", "opta": "glucose is converted to CO2 and H2O", "optb": "NAD+ is reduced to NADH", "optc": "ATP hydrolysis is coupled to sucrose synthesis", "optd": "the terminal phosphate bond of ATP is broken by hydrolysis", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The ability of CTP to bind to aspartate carbamoyltransferase and shut down the synthesis of more CTP is an example of", "opta": "enzyme induction", "optb": "enzyme repression", "optc": "feedback inhibition of enzyme activity", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Oxidation is the", "opta": "loss of proton", "optb": "gain of electron", "optc": "loss of electron", "optd": "gain of protons", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Denaturation of an enzyme refers to the", "opta": "improper arrangement of the enzyme in a metabolic pathway", "optb": "loss of the enzymes proper shape", "optc": "formation of the enzymes proper shape", "optd": "formation of a new isozyme for that enzyme", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}